A Finding Aid to the Charles Rand Penney Papers, 1923-1994, bulk 1945-1994, in the Archives of American Art AAA.pennchar
Archives of American Art
Charles Rand Penney papers
bulk 1945-1994
1923-1994
AAA.pennchar
Archives of American Art
22.9 Linear feet
The papers of art collector Charles Rand Penney measure 22.9 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1994 with the bulk of the collection dating from 1945 to 1994. The majority of the collection consists of Penney's art collection files, which include printed materials, correspondence, notes, and photographic materials. Also found within the papers are catalogs from exhibitions that featured artwork from Penney's collection.
Penney, Charles Rand, 1923-2010
Related Archival Materials note
Also found at the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Charles Rand Penney conducted by Robert F. Brown on August 14-16, 1981. Additional files relating to the Charles Rand Penney Foundation (1963-1976) are located at the Memorial Art Gallery of the University of Rochester in Rochester, N.Y. Files relating to Western New York state artists, Charles Burchfield, and American Arts and Crafts are located at the Burchfield-Penney Center at Buffalo State College, Buffalo, New York.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated in 1993-1994 by Charles Rand Penney.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 2 series.
Series 1: Art Collection Files, 1923-1994 (Box 1-23, OV 24; 22.7 linear feet)
Series 2: Catalogs of the Charles Rand Penney Art Collection, 1966-1991 (Box 23, 0.2 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
Charles Rand Penney (1923-2010) was an art collector from Buffalo, New York. He was well known for his collection of art by Western New York artists, but also collected art from Europe, Africa, Oceania, and other regions of the United States. His travels contributed to the eclectic mix of paintings, drawings, sculptures, hooked rugs, quilts, and tribal art found within his art collection.
Penney cited receiving the watercolor Warrior in 1933 from Western New York artist Bob Blair as the beginning of his life as an art collector. Years later, Penney served in World War II, attended law school, and began practicing law in the 1950s. His collections grew quickly during the late 1950s through 1970s. Penney collected over 100,000 works of art during his lifetime, much of it guided by dealers James and Merle Goodman.
In 1963, Penney began donating artwork to the Memorial Art Gallery in Rochester, New York. In total, approximately 400 works of art were donated to the gallery including Big Diamond by David Smith and Beverly Pepper’s Vertical Ventaglio (1967-1968). Penney also donated over 1000 works of art to the Burchfield Art Center in Buffalo, New York.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art collector Charles Rand Penney measure 22.9 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1994 with the bulk of the collection dating from 1945 to 1994. The collection consists primarily of Penney's art collection files which include printed materials, correspondence, notes, and photographic materials. Also found within the papers are catalogs from exhibitions that featured artwork from Penney's collection.
Artists of significance represented in Penney's art collection files include Jean Arp, John James Audubon, Milton Avery, Harry Beroia, Alexander Calder, Stuart Davis, Philip Evergood, Emil Ganso, Robert Goodnough, Red Grooms, Edward Hopper, John Marin, Reginald Marsh, Joan Miro, Henry Moore, Louise Nevelson, Isamu Noguchi, Beverly Pepper, George Segal, John Sloan, Theodoros Stamos, Saul Steinberg, and Ulfert Wilke, among many others. Also included are files for artists that participated in the Toronto 20 portfolio project in 1965. The files do not include Penney's files relating to Charles Burchfield, Wester New York state artists, or objects from the Arts and Craft movement.
A few notable exhibition catalogs found in the series of catalogs of the Charles Rand Penney art collection are Charles Burchfield: The Charles Rand Penney Collection, The Graphic Art of Emil Ganso, Drawings from the Collection of Charles Rand Penney, Quilts Coverlets Hooked Rugs from the Collection of Charles Rand Penney, The Charles Rand Penney Collection: Twentieth Century Art, and An American Visionary: Watercolors and Drawings of Charles E. Burchfield.
Arp, Jean, 1887-1966; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851; Avery, Milton, 1885-1965; Bertoia, Harry; Burchfield, Charles Ephraim, 1893-1967; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Charles Rand Penney Collection.; Davis, Stuart, 1892-1964; Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973; Ganso, Emil, 1895-1941; Goodnough, Robert, 1917-; Grooms, Red; Hopper, Edward, 1882-1967; Marin, John, 1870-1953; Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954; Miró, Joan, 1893-; Moore, Henry, 1898-; Nevelson, Louise, 1899-1988; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988; Pepper, Beverly; Segal, George, 1924-2000; Sloan, John, 1871-1951; Stamos, Theodoros, 1922-1997; Steinberg, Saul; Wilke, Ulfert, 1907-1987; Art--Collectors and collecting
- Art Collection Files, 1923-1994; Series 1; 22.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-23, OV 24
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged by artist surname.
  Scope and Contents note
  Charles Rand Penney's art collection files are extensive and detailed. They contain printed materials, correspondence, photographic material, and notes about artists, artworks, books, films, galleries, museums, and other projects related to his interests and building his collection of artwork. Files for Toronto 20, a portfolio of lithographs by 20 artists living and working in Toronto, Canada in 1965, include records for 18 of the artists involved in the project along with documents pertaining to Penney's purchase of the Toronto 20 portfolio. Also found within the series is a file containing materials related to exhibitions of Penney's art collection.
  - Adams, Robert, 1962-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ahlgren, Roy B., 1969-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - Altman, Harold (Box 1)
    - General, 1961-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arnot Art Gallery, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Associated American Artists, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Biographical Information, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - G Contemporary Paintings, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hole Mark Graphics, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Multiple Impressions, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Nan Miller Gallery, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Newmark Gallery, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Passage (1961) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Schuman Gallery, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Seated Woman, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Summa Gallery, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Weyhe Gallery, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Antes, Horst, 1967-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Anuszkiewicz, Richard, 1965-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Appel, Karel (Box 1)
    - General, 1963-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Associated American Artists, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Gallery Moos Limited, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Gimpel Fils Gallery, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - James Goodman Gallery, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Marisa Del Re Gallery, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Passage a Nuit (1960), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Armitage, Kenneth (Box 1)
    - General, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Seated Group Listening to Music (1952), 1965-1986 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Seated Woman with Arms Extended (1953-1957), 1962-1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Arms, John Taylor (Box 1)
    - General, 1971-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Associated American Artists, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Georgia Museum of Art at University of Georgia, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Kennedy Galleries, Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Memorial Art Gallery, Lending and Sales Gallery, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - St. Paul, Alpes Martimes, France (1927), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Ward M. Canaday Gift to College of Wooster Art Center, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Arp, Jean (Box 1)
    - General, 1966-1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Claude Bernard Gallery, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Coeur de Fruit (1960), 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Dominion Gallery, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Gallery Moos Limited, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Guggenheim Museum, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - James Goodman, Inc., 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Obituary, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Post Cards, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Profile, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Sidney Janis Gallery, 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Tete-Bouteille et Moustache, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Weintraub Gallery, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Audubon, John James (Box 1)
    - General, 1963-1988 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - 200th Birthday, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Audubon, John James (Box 2)
    - The Amsterdam Edition of the Elephant Folio, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Birds of America, Octavo Edition, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Birds of America, Sale of Artwork in New York, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Bonaparte Audubon Prints, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Hummingbird, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Swallow-Tailed Hawk, First Edition, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Swallow-Tailed Hawk, Octavo Edition, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Violet-Green Swallow, Octavo Edition, 1961-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - White Headed Eagle (1828), 1966-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Avery, Milton (Box 2)
    - General, 1967-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
    - Beach Birds (1954), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Contemplative Bird (1959), 1964-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fishing (1944), 1964-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Paintings and Watercolors" (1989) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Retrospective Exhibition (1982), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Rothko with Pipe (1936), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Three Birds (1952), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ault, George C. (Box 2)
    - General, 1973-1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Barn at Woodstock (1940), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Vanderwoude/Tananbaum Gallery, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Zabriskie Gallery, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ayrton, Michael, 1965-1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bacon, Peggy, 1972-1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Baj, Enrico, 1969-1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Barnet, Will, 1972-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
  - Barrymore, Lionel, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bartlett, William H., Prints, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Baskin, Leonard (Box 2)
    - General, 1967-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1969 Gold Medal for Graphic Arts, The National Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Associated American Artists, 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bertolt Brecht (1952), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Grace Borgenicht Gallery, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Kennedy Galleries, 1971-1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Midtown Payson Galleries, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - The Mysterious Rebe of Northampton, Mass (1964), circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Self Portrait (1971), 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bellows, George Wesley (Box 2)
    - General, 1966-1992 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Bellows, George Wesley (Box 3)
    - H.V. Allison Galleries, Inc., 1963-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Letter to Dr. and Mrs. Harold Rifkin from Penney, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - National Portrait Gallery, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Paul Magriel, Art Collector, 1965-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Portrait of Mr. Rosen (1923), 1963-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Salamander O'Reilly Galleries, Inc., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Spanierman Gallery, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Berge, Edward, General, 1968-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Berge, Edward, Exhibition of American Sculpture Catalog (1923), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Benton, Thomas Hart (Box 3)
    - General, 1970-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - America Today, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Approaching Storm (1938), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Boomtown (1927-1928), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sylvan Cole Gallery, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Thomas Hart Benton: An American Original" (1989-1990) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Bertoia, Harry (Box 3)
    - General, 1963-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Benjamin Mangel Gallery, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cranbrook, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Diamond Chair (1952), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Furniture, 1962-1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Hokin Gallery, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - M & T Fountain (1968), 1967-1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Sculpture at Princeton University Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs (1964), circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Sid Deutsch Gallery, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Sound Sculpture, 1973-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Staempfli Gallery, 1967-1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Storm King Art Center, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Untitled (1954-1955), 1965-1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Biddle, George, 1972-1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bill, Max, 1966-1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bishop, Isabel (Box 3)
    - General, 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1971-1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Associated American Artists, 1973-1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Deep Sleep (1931), 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Dorsky Gallery, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Little Nude (1964), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Midtown Galleries, 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Obituary, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Subway Riders (1944), 1973-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Two Women, Union Square Wall (1935), 1972-1990 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Woman's Art Journal Editorial Board List, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Women's Caucus for Art, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Bluemner, Oscar (Box 3)
    - General, 1973-1989 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Andrew Crispo Gallery, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Archives of American Art, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Barbara Mathes Gallery, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Bernard Danenberg Galleries, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Davis Galleries, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Graham Gallery, 1967-1987 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Linda Hyman Fine Arts, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Owen Gallery, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Richard York Gallery, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Sid Deutsch Gallery, 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Terry Dintenfass, Inc., 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Venus (1924), Exhibition Loan to Ramapo College Art Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Venus (1924), Purchase from James Goodman Gallery, 1965-1989 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Boni, Paolo (Box 3)
    - General, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 65-66)
    - Associated American Artists, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Autre Reve, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Boni, Paolo (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Instituto Italiano di Cultura, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Penn Atelier Graphics, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Poster, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Print Club of Cleveland, circa 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Recueillement (1966), circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Untitled (1969), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Boon, Martyn T., 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brussel-Smith, Bernard, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bury, Pol, 1965-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Butler, Reginald, General, 1965-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Butler, Reginald, Storm King Art Center, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Caesar, Doris, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cadmus, Paul (Box 4)
    - General, 1973-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Fleet's In (1934), 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Midtown Galleries, 1972-1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Paul Cadmus: Enfant Terrible at 80, Film by David Sutherland, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Calder, Alexander (Box 4)
    - General, 1966-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
    - 75th Birthday, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Albert White Gallery, 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1971-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - A. Stirling Calder, Father, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Barbara Mathes Gallery, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Braniff's Bicentennial Plane 727, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Calder Piece by Earle Brown, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Calder's Universe" (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Circus, 1970-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Death of the Artist, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Donald Morris Gallery, circa 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Empire State Plaza, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "Expo 67" (1967) (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Grand Rapids, Michigan Stabile (1969), 1969-1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Guggenheim Museum, 1968-1984 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Gwenfritz (1968), Dedication, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Hanging Mobile (1952), circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - James Goodman Gallery, circa 1966 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      Oversized material housed in OV 24.
    - Jean Davidson, Son-In-Law, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Jewelry, 1966-1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - The Jousters (1963), Art Exchange, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - The Jousters (1963), Letter Regarding Tax, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Jousters (1963), Loans, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - The Jousters (1963), Miscellaneous, 1968-1989 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - The Jousters (1963), Photographs and Negatives, 1963-1980 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - The Jousters (1963), Purchase, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Marisa Del Re Gallery, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - M. Knoedler and Co., 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Mobilia (1979), Film by Nancy E. Burke, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1968-1982 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - New York Times Magazine, 1970-1985 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - The Pace Gallery, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Perls Galleries, 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 56-57)
    - Posters, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Prints and Illustrated Books, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Publications, circa 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Save the Calder Circus, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 61-62)
    - Sidewalk, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Storm King Art Center, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Tapestries, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - University of Indiana, Bloomington, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Untitled (1963), 1965-1991 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1966-1991 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - William Beadleston, Inc., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Canade, Vincent, 1964-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Caro, Anthony (Box 5)
    - General, 1973-1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Bronze Sculpture" (1980) at Aquavella Contemmporary Art, Inc., 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Catalogues, 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "From the Figure" (1986) at Aquavella Contemporary Art, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Table Piece CCCCIII (1977-1978), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Castellon, Federico, 1981-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Catlin, George, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chadwick, Lynn (Box 5)
    - Beast (circa 1959), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Black Beast, 1959-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Galleries, 1972-1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Photographic Materials, 1970-1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Publicity, 1965-1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Red and Black, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - St. Louis Sculpture Park, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cheffetz, Asa, circa 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cocteau, Jean (Box 5)
    - General, 1964-1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Caprone (1962), 1964-1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Edigio Constantini, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Murano Glass, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Murano Glass by Picasso, Gift to Albright-Knox Art Gallery by Mrs. Samuel C. Miller, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Peggy Guggenheim, 1965-1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "The Poetry of Jean Cocteau" (1989) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Sculpture in Glass" (1965-1966) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cole, Timothy, 1980-1988 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Conley, Steve, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Connell, Clyde, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Consagra, Pietro, 1970-1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Cook, Howard Norton, General, 1945-1987 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Cook, Howard Norton, Old Print Shop, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Corneille, Guillaume Beverloo, 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Cornell, Joseph (Box 5)
    - General, 1967-1989 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - ACA Galleries, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Barbara Mathes Gallery, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - "The Early Collages" (1980), 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Leo Castelli, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - The Pace Gallery, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Retrospective Exhibition (1980-1981) (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Currier and Ives, Prints, 1973-1988 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Dalwood, Hubert, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Davies, Arthur Bowen, 1965-1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Davis, Lee Baxter, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dali, Salvadore (Box 6)
    - General, 1960-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - Apollinaire I (1968), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Biographical Information, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Death of the Artist, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Davis, Stuart (Box 6)
    - General, 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Archives of American Art, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Associated American Artists, 1981-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Babe La Tour (1912-1913), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Backyard Staircases (1917), 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Catalogue Raisonne, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Death of the Artist, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Downtown Gallery, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Fogg Art Museum, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Grace Borgenicht Gallery, 1979-1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Hill Road (1917), 1964-1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Lawrence Rubin Gallery, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mary Ryan Gallery, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Memorial Art Gallery, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Salander-O'Reilly Galleries, 1985-1993 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Sid Deutsch Gallery, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "Stuart Davis' New York" (1986) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Susan Sheehan, Inc., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - U.S. Postage Stamp, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Washburn Gallery, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 32)